Guide to the Ira Unschuld Collection of Print Club of New York Presentation Prints 1994-2015 PR 388
New-York Historical Society
Ira Unschuld collection of Print Club of New York presentation prints
1994-2015
New-York Historical Society
Print Club of New York
Unschuld, Ira L.
PR 388
3 Linear feet in one flat file folder
The Print Club of New York annually commissions an artist to create a print for presentation to each of its 200 members. This collection holds ten of these prints.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in chronological order.
Biographical / Historical
The Print Club of New York was founded in 1991. Membership is limited to 200. Among the club's activities is the annual selection of an artist for a commission to create a print presented to each member. Information about the club and the presentation prints created for the club over the years can be found at their website.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. Contact the Print Room Reference Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ira L. Unschuld, 2013, 2014, and 2017.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes ten presentation prints commissioned by The Print Club of New York. The specific prints held are listed individually in the container list below.
Printmakers; Prints (visual works).; Booker, Chakaia, 1953-; Flack, Audrey; Jenkins, Paul, 1923-2012; Katz, Alex, 1927-; McPherson, Craig, 1948-; Ringgold, Faith; Segalman, Richard, 1934-; Snyder, Joan, 1940-; Teskey, Donald; Walker, John, 1939-
- Katz, Alex. Jessica, 1994 (Folder FF-1)
  Scope and Contents
  3 color woodcut. 47/200.
- Jenkins, Paul. At Stroke of Twelve, 1999 (Folder FF-1)
  Color lithograph. Produced at Atelier Franck Bordas, Paris. 127/200.
- Walker, John. Diagonal Hollyhocks, 2003 (Folder FF-1)
  Hand-colored aquatint. Master Printer: James Stroud. 100/200.
- Snyder, Joan. Oasis, 2006 (Folder FF-1)
  4-color silkscreen and prismacolor hand addition. Master Printer: Randy Hemminghaus of the Rutgers Center for Innovative Print and Paper. 170/200.
- Segalman, Richard. Coney Island, 2008 (Folder FF-1)
  Aluminum plate lithograph. Printed at Interbang Press in Santa Fe. Printed on Rives BFK paper. 152/200.
- McPherson, Craig. New York Water Tunnel, 2009 (Folder FF-1)
  Mezzotint. 28/200.
- Booker, Chakaia. Untitled., 2011 (Folder FF-1)
  4 block woodcut with 65 piece chine collé. Master Printers: Phil Sanders, Sam Chun, and Chris Dunnett, at Robert Blackburn Printmaking Workshop. 20.5 x 25". 43/200.
- Flack, Audrey. Un Bouchée d'Amour, 2013 (Folder FF-1)
  Screenprint with digitized drawing. Master Printer: Jase Clark, Experimental Printmaking Institute, Lafayette College. Canson Infinity Etching Rag Paper 310g. Sheet: 21 x 18"; Image 15.5 x18 ". 94/200.
- Ringgold, Faith. Here Comes Moses, 2014 (Folder FF-1)
  From Jones Road series. Screenprint. Master Printers: Curlee Raven Holton and Jase Clark, Experimental Printmaking Institute, Lafayette College. 196/200.
- Teskey, Donald. Untitled., 2015 (Folder FF-1)
  Carborundum and intaglio. Master Printer: Kelvin Mann at Stoney Road Press, Dublin, Ireland. Hahnemühle German etching paper 310 gsm. Sheet: 22.6 x 20.8" (57.5 x 53 cm); Plate: 12.4 x 12.8" (31.5 x 32.5 cm). 148/200.